At last, there's nobody here but us.
Father...
Sorry to make you wait.
Listen, Historia...
This may sound very strange to you,
but Frieda is not entirely dead.
Eh?
The memories of Frieda still live on.
Would you like to meet your sister?
Yes!
Understand, Eren?!
You'll be the one to avenge your mother!
They got in?
That's...
What are those?
Fire arrow?
Gunpowder?!
By the burning pattern, they must
have scattered bags full of oil...
This could get ugly!
Here they come!
Shoot 'em down!
Smoke signal shells?!
Tsk! We'll never hit a thing in all this smoke.
Twenty-four.
Thirty-two.
Thirty-five enemies!
They're gathered behind the pillars!
Continue the plan!
We'll take 'em all out right here!
All troops, spread out!
Surround them one at a time!
More smoke?!
Shit! Where'd they go?!
A big weakness of the
Anti-Personnel ODM gear is...
...their line of fire and anchor trajectory
are both faced in the same direction.
In other words, the area directly behind
them is completely out of their reach.
Over there! Fire!
I missed?!
Where are they?!
You're mine!
Sasha!
Conny! Hide in the smoke and fight!
Take this!
Shit!
But their greatest weakness is...
once they've fired off two shots...
...it takes a while for them to reload.
This ain't looking good.
The hell's with that girl?!
When they manage to get this close,
swords have the advantage!
We've gotta stop 'em!
At this rate, we'll get wiped out!
Yo, Levi.
Not that I've got time to waste on you, but...
If you get past here, it'll all be for nothin'.
So be it. Guess I'll have to play.
Neener, neener, neener!
You're a spunky one, damn.
Tsk!
Not sick of playing yet? Good grief.
Didn't I teach you?!
When chasing an enemy,
don't just stare straight ahead!
Over here, dimwit!
You... bastard.
That really hurt!
If I can force one of them
to show a small opening...
Huh? Both of your shots were way off!
You like to live recklessly, too?!
Argh!
Hange!
Now! Fall back to the final defensive post!
Time to regroup!
Tsk!
Stay out of the way, you little runt.
Ouch...
Drop it!
Guard the ritual, Captain!
Yeah, that's where I'll be!
"Syringe" "A device Rod Reiss wants Historia Reiss
to use and transform into a Titan. It is believed to
use spinal fluid, and by injecting the transformation
serum, one is granted the inherent abilities of a Titan."
It seems the enemy is nearby.
Let's hurry, Historia.
Right.
What, Eren? Why are you glaring?
It's because... he has perceived his fate.
That the stolen power will
return to where it belongs.
Historia...
That means inside you.
Eh?
This cavern... It was built around 100
years ago by the power of a certain Titan.
Those three walls were built by the same power.
By creating those enormous walls,
humanity was protected.
The power of that Titan reached out to touch
people's hearts and alter their memories.
However, several bloodlines
were excluded from that.
But their descendants and
the rest of humanity...
...retain no history of the
world past a century ago.
Except for one, Frieda Reiss.
Frieda possessed more
than her power as a Titan.
She knew how this world came about
and all the details behind it.
She was 15 years old when
that knowledge became hers.
Right here, eight years ago in this very place...
...after she ate her uncle, my younger brother.
Frieda inherited the Founding Titan
and the memories of this world.
As had been done for 100 years,
repeated and passed through generations.
Father...
Yes...
Basically, if Frieda had just used her power,
there wouldn't have been any problems.
We might have eliminated Titans
from this world entirely.
If only his father hadn't stolen
the power from her.
Now, that power resides within Eren.
However, that power...
It can't truly manifest unless the blood
of the Reiss family runs through them.
As long as he remains a vessel for that power...
...this hell will forever continue.
Eh?
Then...
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Kenny.
So unless it's a Reiss who eats Eren,
they can't become a true King?
That is correct.
Th-Then... even if I turn into a Titan
and eat Eren, it'll mean nothin'?
What are you--?
Father!
Do you think I'm lying to you or something?
Nope.
I waited long for this day 'cuz I knew you
weren't lying about the succession ritual.
For crying out loud!
You used me this whole time knowing full well
what I was after, you sleazy playboy!
I'm grateful for you.
You may have been a stray dog that my
whimsical younger brother took in, but--
Keep on insulting Uri, and you can
say goodbye to half of your head.
Stop it!
Let my father go!
Huh? You're plain pitiful, Historia.
Don't you get it?!
This father of yours wants to turn you
into a monster and make you eat Eren.
Because that's my duty.
Yes...
I'm going to eat Eren and bring my sister back.
I'll inherit the world's history and
exterminate every last Titan!
That's my duty!
Hey, hey, Historia!
Have you forgotten everything
this guy has done to you?
The only thing he cares about
is the blood inside you.
He doesn't wanna become a Titan himself!
He's just trash that forces
his brother and daughter to!
That's this father of yours!
He's wrong, Historia...
I must not become a Titan myself.
Do not believe... what anyone else says...
Oh, is that right?
Father!
Kenny.
You've served well up until now.
You're free now.
Go find another purpose in life...
and live out your years.
That would bore me to death.
Kenny! What are you doing?
Go ahead and turn into a Titan.
I won't interfere anymore.
However, no head starts.
You both become Titans and have at it.
If Historia wins, you'll have your peace.
But if you lose to Eren,
the situation stays the same.
Keep drawing breath till I run out and die?
Can you even call that livin'?!
Historia!
With this injection, you can
become a powerful Titan!
Then you can eat him,
but in fact, it's more than that!
You must bite his spine
and consume the spinal fluid!
Whoops, better step back.
Hurry up, Historia!
Eren, why?!
Why aren't you transforming?!
If I become a Titan, you'll get eaten!
At this rate...
Do it, Historia!
It shouldn't have happened...
Eh?
Me...
My dad, too...
If five years ago, he hadn't done that here...
Your sister... would have been
able to do something, right?
But my dad stole the Power of
the Titans from its rightful place.
Just how many died for that?
Armin's grandpa...
Thomas, Nack, Mina, Milieus...
Marco... Those guys on Squad Levi...
The people of Stohess...
Those soldiers who came to save me...
Mr. Hannes...
I can never atone for it all.
It shouldn't have happened...
Those days of training...
That dream beyond the walls...
I... shouldn't have happened.
So, at the least...
...let it end at your hand.
Eat me.
Save humanity.
It's all... up to you.
Eren...
That time...
...when you called me a normal
person, I was so happy.
So you're trying to do something "nice," huh?
What's wrong, Historia? Are you scared?
All you have to do is inject
that liquid into your body.
Father...
Why?
Why didn't the Reiss family...
in that whole 100 years...
...eliminate the Titans and liberate humanity?
All while possessing the power
to control all the Titans...
Because, the first Reiss King who
built this world within the walls...
...wished for us to be controlled by the Titans.
The first King believed that was
the only path to true peace.
But I do not know why.
It's only known by those who
see the world's memories.
Long ago, I...
...along with my brother, pleaded with our
father to free humanity from the Titans...
...time and time again.
However, he would not fulfill our wish.
Eventually, it came time for
my father to pass on that role.
When my brother inherited the Power of
the Titans and I looked into his eyes...
...I understood what that meant.
To create this world...
To govern its very foundation...
To be an omnipotent being
is to be what my brother became.
Do you know what we call that?
God.
What we call that... is God.
And my duty is to bring God back to
our world and offer them my prayers.
I'm praying, Historia.
For God to lead and guide humanity!
Christa.
I have no right to tell you
how to live your life.
So actually, this is nothing more
than a hope of mine...
I want you... to live a life you're proud of.
Historia!
God, my ass! You're just giving yourself
an out and manipulating other people!
I've had it! I won't let you kill me!
That's the spirit! This is gettin' good!
What are you doing, Historia?!
Eren, we're leaving.
Hey, stop it!
If I go on living, everyone will keep suffering!
Hurry up and eat me!
I can't take living like this!
Shut up, idiot! Just shut up, crybaby!
Exterminate the Titans?!
Who the hell wants to do that bullshit?!
I'm starting to hate humanity!
Let 'em get wiped out by Titans!
I'm humanity's biggest enemy!
Got it?! I'm the worst girl who ever lived!
You escape from here.
I'll destroy everything else!
Father...
Uri...
Frieda...
Wait for me...
I'll... now...
Rod Reiss becomes a Titan.
To protect Mikasa and the others from a cave-in,
Eren is cornered by another decision.
Next episode: "Outside the
Walls of Orvud District."